Register of the Mont Pèlerin Society records
Hoover Institution Archives
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1946-1978 (Boxes 29-44)
  - Hunold, Albert (Secretary, 1948-1960; Vice-President, 1960-1962)
    - 1950
      - Conference sponsored by the Abteilung für Volkswirtschaftliche Studien of the Schweizerisches Institut für Auslandforschung, "Planwirtschaft, Inflation und Beschäftigungspolitik," Zurich, Switzerland, August 25 (Box-folder 31: 11)
        Includes notes and clipping.
    - 1951
      - General
        - A-B (Box-folder 32: 1)
        - C-F (Box-folder 32: 2)
        - G-H (Box-folder 32: 3)
        - I-L (Box-folder 32: 4)
        - M-P (Box-folder 32: 5)
        - R-W (Box-folder 32: 6)
      - Kölner Tagung, sponsored by the Institut für Wirtschaftspolitik an der Universität Köln, May 2-3 (Box-folder 32: 7)
    - 1952
      - General
        - A-E (Box-folder 32: 8)
        - F-K (Box-folder 32: 9)
        - L-W (Box-folder 32: 10)
      - Tagung ausländischer und schweizerischer Nationalökonomen, "Einkommensverteilung und Besteuerung," sponsored by the Abteilung für Volkswirtschaftliche Studien of the Schweizerisches Institut für Auslandforschung, Zurich, Switzerland, July 5 (Box-folder 32: 11)
        Includes papers by Friedrich A. von Hayek and Gottfried Haberler, notes by Albert Hunold, and clippings.
    - 1953
      - A-B (Box-folder 32: 12)
      - C-F (Box-folder 33: 1)
      - G-H (Box-folder 33: 2)
      - J-L (Box-folder 33: 3)
      - M (Box-folder 33: 4)
      - N-R (Box-folder 33: 5)
      - S-W (Box-folder 33: 6)
    - 1953-1954 - Library
      - A-C (Box-folder 33: 7)
      - D-H (Box-folder 33: 8)
      - I-P (Box-folder 33: 9)
      - R-Y (Box-folder 33: 10)
    - 1954
      - A-B (Box-folder 33: 11)
      - C-D (Box-folder 33: 12)
      - E-F (Box-folder 34: 1)
      - G (Box-folder 34: 2)
      - H-I (Box-folder 34: 3)
      - K-M (Box-folder 34: 4)
      - N-R (Box-folder 34: 5)
      - S-W (Box-folder 34: 6)
    - 1955
      - A-B (Box-folder 34: 7)
      - C-F (Box-folder 34: 8)
      - G-H (Box-folder 34: 9)
      - I-J (Box-folder 34: 10)
      - K-L (Box-folder 34: 11)
      - M (Box-folder 35: 1)
      - N-W (Box-folder 35: 2)
    - 1956
      - January-June
        - A-G (Box-folder 35: 3)
        - H-L (Box-folder 35: 4)
        - M-W (Box-folder 35: 5)
      - July-December
        - A-B (Box-folder 35: 6)
        - C-F (Box-folder 35: 7)
        - G-H (Box-folder 35: 8)
        - I-M (Box-folder 35: 9)
        - N-W (Box-folder 35: 10)
    - 1957
      - General
        - January-June
          - A-C (Box-folder 36: 1)
          - D-G (Box-folder 36: 2)
          - H-J (Box-folder 36: 3)
          - K-M (Box-folder 36: 4)
          - N-S (Box-folder 36: 5)
          - T-Z (Box-folder 36: 6)
        - July-December
          - A-B (Box-folder 36: 7)
          - C-F (Box-folder 36: 8)
          - G-K (Box-folder 36: 9)
          - L-N (Box-folder 37: 1)
          - O-R (Box-folder 37: 2)
          - S-Z (Box-folder 37: 3)
      - Federal Republic of Germany. Bundesministerium für Wirtschaft (Rolf Gocht, Dr. Weber), 1957-1959 (Box-folder 37: 4)
    - 1958
      - General
        - January-June
          - A-C (Box-folder 37: 5)
          - D-F (Box-folder 37: 6)
          - G-L (Box-folder 37: 7)
          - M-W (Box-folder 37: 8)
        - July-December
          - A-F (Box-folder 37: 9)
          - G-J (Box-folder 37: 10)
          - K-L (Box-folder 37: 11)
          - M-R (Box-folder 38: 1)
          - S-Y (Box-folder 38: 2)
      - Princeton Meeting
        - General (Box-folder 38: 3-4)
        - A-B (Box-folder 38: 5)
        - C-G (Box-folder 38: 6)
        - H-K (Box-folder 38: 7)
        - L-N (Box-folder 38: 8)
        - O-S (Box-folder 38: 9)
        - T-Y (Box-folder 38: 10)
    - 1959
      - Members
        - January-June
          - A-B (Box-folder 39: 1)
          - C-E (Box-folder 39: 2)
          - F (Box-folder 39: 3)
          - G-J (Box-folder 39: 4)
          - K-L (Box-folder 39: 5)
          - M-N (Box-folder 39: 6)
          - O-S (Box-folder 39: 7)
          - T-Z (Box-folder 39: 8)
        - July-December
          - A-B (Box-folder 39: 9)
          - C-G (Box-folder 39: 10)
          - H-L (Box-folder 39: 11)
          - M-P (Box-folder 40: 1)
          - R (Box-folder 40: 2)
          - S-Z (Box-folder 40: 3)
      - Non-members
        - General
          - A-D (Box-folder 40: 4)
          - E-H (Box-folder 40: 5)
          - I-K (Box-folder 40: 6)
          - L-R (Box-folder 40: 7)
          - R-S (Box-folder 40: 8)
          - T-Z (Box-folder 40: 9)
        - Arbeitsgemeinschaft Selbständiger Unternehmer e. V. (Box-folder 40: 10)
        - Association de l'Entreprise à Capital Personnel (Box-folder 40: 11)
          Includes some 1960 correspondence.
        - Conference of American Small Business Organizations (Box-folder 41: 1)
        - International Council for Free Enterprise (Box-folder 41: 2)
        - Unione Christiana Imprenditori Dirigenti (Box-folder 41: 3)
          Includes some 1960-1961 correspondence.
    - 1960
      - General
        - January-June
          - A-B (Box-folder 41: 4)
          - C-G (Box-folder 41: 5)
          - H-L (Box-folder 41: 6)
          - M-R (Box-folder 41: 7)
          - S-W (Box-folder 41: 8)
        - July-September
          - A-B (Box-folder 41: 9)
          - C-G (Box-folder 41: 10)
          - H-K (Box-folder 41: 11)
          - L-O (Box-folder 41: 12)
          - P-T (Box-folder 42: 1)
          - U-Z (Box-folder 42: 2)
        - October-December
          - A-H (Box-folder 42: 3)
          - K-P (Box-folder 42: 4)
          - R-Z (Box-folder 42: 5)
      - European section (Box-folder 42: 6-8)
    - 1961 - Stiftung Schloss Lenzburg (Box-folder 42: 9)
    - 1961-1963
      Includes correspondence with non-members, and some 1959-1960 correspondence.
      - A-B (Box-folder 42: 10)
      - C-E (Box-folder 42: 11)
      - F-G (Box-folder 42: 12)
      - H (Box-folder 43: 1)
      - I-L (Box-folder 43: 2)
      - M-N (Box-folder 43: 3)
      - O-R (Box-folder 43: 4)
      - S (Box-folder 43: 5)
      - T-Z (Box-folder 43: 6)
    - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 43: 7)
      After Albert Hunold left the Society.
    - 1978 (Box-folder 43: 8)
      Miscellaneous family correspondence.
  - Leoni, Bruno (Secretary, 1960-1967)
    - 1961-1963 (Box-folder 43: 9)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 43: 10)
    - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 43: 11)
      Includes newspaper account of his death, 23 November 1967.
  - Harris, Ralph (Secretary, 1967-1976)
    - 1968-1971 (Box-folder 44: 1)
    - 1972-1977 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Jewkes, John (President, 1962-1964) (Box-folder 44: 3)
- NEWSLETTER FILE, 1973-1989 (Boxes 44-48)
  Background material, clippings, and correspondence of Eric Brodin, editor of The Mont Pèlerin Society Newsletter, as well as some issues of the newsletter (published by the Society since 1971). Arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Background material (Box-folder 44: 4-9)
    Announcements, brochures, clippings, obituaries, papers, etc. for inclusion in The Mont Pèlerin Society Newsletter.
  - Background material (Box-folder 45: 1-9)
  - Background material (Box-folder 46: 1-4)
  - Correspondence of Eric Brodin, editor
    - 1978-1983 (Box-folder 47: 1)
    - 1984 (Box-folder 47: 2-3)
    - 1985 (Box-folder 47: 4-6)
    - 1986 (Box-folder 47: 7-8)
    - 1987 (Box-folder 47: 9)
    - 1988 (Box-folder 47: 10)
    - 1989 (Box-folder 47: 11)
  - List of publications by members, 1987 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Notes by Eric Brodin, undated (Box-folder 48: 2)
  - Obituaries, 1981-1987 (Box-folder 48: 3)
  - Printed copies of the newsletter, 1973-1987 (Box-folder 48: 4)
- TREASURERS' FILE, 1949-1981 (Boxes 48-58)
  Annual reports; bank statements; check stubs; correspondence of successive treasurers; grant proposals, particularly with the Relm Foundation; deposit slips; income tax material; membership file; paid bills; reports; and vouchers. Arranged alphabetically by physical form.
  - Annual reports
    - 1949-1968 (Box-folder 48: 5)
    - 1969-1978 (Box-folder 48: 6)
  - Bank statements
    - General
      - 1950-1952 (Box-folder 48: 7)
      - 1953-1954 (Box-folder 48: 8)
      - 1955-1957 (Box-folder 48: 9)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 48: 10)
      - 1960-1961 (Box-folder 48: 11)
      - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 48: 12)
      - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 48: 13)
      - 1966-1967 (Box-folder 48: 14)
      - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 48: 15)
      - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 49: 1)
      - 1971-1972 (Box-folder 49: 2)
      - 1972-1973 (Box-folder 49: 3)
      - 1978 (Box-folder 49: 4)
      - 1978-1979 (Box-folder 49: 5)
    - Hunold, Albert, 1958 (Box-folder 49: 6)
    - Leoni, Bruno, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 49: 7)
  - Check stubs
    - 1950 (Box-folder 50: 1)
    - 1954 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - 1958 (Box-folder 50: 3)
    - 1959-1962 (Box-folder 50: 4)
    - 1965 (Box-folder 50: 5)
    - 1976-1978 (Box-folder 50: 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Wallis, W. Allen (Treasurer, 1948-1954)
      - 1950-1952 (Box-folder 50: 7)
      - 1953 (Box-folder 50: 8)
      - 1954 (Box-folder 50: 9)
      - 1955 (Box-folder 50: 10)
      - 1956 (Box-folder 50: 11)
    - Machlup, Fritz (Treasurer, 1954-1959)
      - 1955-1957 (Box-folder 50: 12)
      - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 50: 13-14)
    - Philbrook, Clarence E. (Treasurer, 1959-1969)
      - General
        - 1959-1960 (Box-folder 51: 1)
        - 1961 (Box-folder 51: 2-3)
        - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 51: 4)
        - 1965-1966 (Box-folder 51: 5)
        - 1967-1968 (Box-folder 51: 6)
      - Harris, Ralph (Secretary, 1967-1976), 1966-1968 (Box-folder 51: 7)
    - Kemp, Arthur (Treasurer, 1969-1979)
      - General
        - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 51: 8)
        - 1968-1969 (Box-folder 51: 9)
        - 1970 (Box-folder 51: 10)
        - 1971 (Box-folder 52: 1)
        - 1972 (Box-folder 52: 2)
        - 1973 (Box-folder 52: 3)
        - 1974 (Box-folder 52: 4-5)
        - 1975 (Box-folder 52: 6)
        - 1976 (Box-folder 52: 7)
        - 1977 (Box-folder 52: 8-9)
        - 1978 (Box-folder 53: 1)
        - 1979 (Box-folder 53: 2)
      - French section, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 53: 3)
      - Hamilius, Jean-Pierre (Assistant Secretary, 1972-1977)
        - 1972 (Box-folder 53: 4)
        - 1973 (Box-folder 53: 5)
        - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 53: 6)
    - Feulner, Edwin (1979- )
      - 1979 (Box-folder 53: 7)
      - 1980 (Box-folder 53: 8)
      - 1981 (Box-folder 54: 1-2)
  - Deposit slips, 1959-1969 (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - Grant proposals
    - General, 1962 (Box-folder 54: 4)
    - Lilly Endowment, 1964-1973 (Box-folder 54: 5)
    - Relm Foundation
      - 1959 (Box-folder 54: 6)
      - 1961 (Box-folder 54: 7)
      - 1964 (Box-folder 54: 8)
      - 1965 (Box-folder 54: 9)
      - 1966 (Box-folder 55: 1)
      - 1967 (Box-folder 55: 2)
      - 1968 (Box-folder 55: 3)
      - 1969 (Box-folder 55: 4)
      - 1970 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Income tax file
    - General (Box-folder 55: 6)
    - Returns
      - 1951-1958 (Box-folder 55: 7)
      - 1958-1965 (Box-folder 55: 8)
      - 1965-1969 (Box-folder 55: 9)
      - 1967-1969 (Box-folder 56: 1)
      - 1969-1972 (Box-folder 56: 2)
      - 1973-1974 (Box-folder 56: 3)
      - 1974-1975 (Box-folder 56: 4)
      - 1975-1976 (Box-folder 56: 5)
      - 1976 (Box-folder 56: 6)
      - 1977-1978 (Box-folder 56: 7)
  - List of delinquent members (Box-folder 56: 8)
  - Membership file
    - 1948-1964 (Box-folder 56: 9-10)
    - 1949-1950 (Box-folder 57: 1)
    - 1951 (Box-folder 57: 2)
    - 1952-1954 (Box-folder 57: 3)
    - 1955-1958 (Box-folder 57: 4)
    - 1959-1961 (Box-folder 57: 5)
    - 1962-1963 (Box-folder 57: 6)
    - 1965-1974 (Box-folder 57: 7)
  - Paid bills, 1959-1964 (Box-folder 57: 8)
  - Records of Albert Hunold, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 58: 1-2)
    Consists mainly of correspondence with treasurers.
  - Vouchers
    - 1958-1959 (Box-folder 58: 3)
    - 1960-1969 (Box-folder 59: 4)
- FILMSTRIPS, undated (Box 59)
  Thirty-four filmstrips taken at various meetings. Includes filmstrip of Albert Hunold in Lappland.
- SOUND RECORDINGS, 1956-1966 (Boxes 60-63)
  Fifty-four sound tape reels, mostly of proceedings of meetings and speeches by various individuals.
  - Mont Pèlerin Society meeting at Berlin, Germany, 1956 August-September (Box 60)
    Access
    Use copy reference number: 81123_a_0005657
    Part 1
    Unidentified German speaker speaking in English on permanent inflation; the chairman, Hunold covering administrative issues; Professor Baudin speaking in French without translation; and Müller-Armack responding to permanent inflation and the policies of the German government.
    Part 2
    Description is currently unavailable.
    Part 3
    Part 4
    Part 5
    Unidentified French speaker; a woman speaking on the Cuban situation towards communism; an unidentified German speaker, and following English translation, on outlawing political parties; an unidentified English speaker on outlawing political parties; an unidentified German speaker, and following English translation, on implications of the industrial revolution; an unidentified English speaker on the difference between the Socialist and Communist parties in America; an unidentified speaker with a Mexican accent; an unidentified English speaker on the previous day’s issues; and an unidentified English speaker on Communism in Sweden.
    Part 6
    The majority is a discussion chaired by Ludwig von Mises about the welfare state. There are many speakers, most unidentified, including Mises and F. A. Hayek. Before this session on the tape, Mises talks on the uselessness of outlawing communist parties in fighting communism.
    Part 7
    Part 8
    Part 9
    For the majority of this recording, Hayek discusses traditional liberalism. He identifies its past and how it relates to contemporary thought and trends. The overreaching theme of his talk, as he mentions at the beginning, is to analyze these things so that liberals can present their views without referring to the classical champions of the philosophy and increase the popularity of liberalism.
    Part 10
    Hayek excerpt, unidentified German speaker, discussion of administrative issues.
  - Mont Pèlerin Society meeting at Princeton, New Jersey, 1958 September 8-13 (Box 60)
    Use copy reference number: 81123_a_0003834
    1958 September 8, P.M. session. Opening greeting by Professor F. A. Hayek and Princeton Professor Gardner Patterson. Addresses by Ludwig von Mises, "Liberty and Property," Pierre Goodrich, Felix Morley, "Meaning of Freedom."
    1958 September 9, A.M. session. Discussions on the welfare state, following papers by W. Hagenbuch (Cambridge, England) and W. Röpke (Geneva).
    F. A. Hayek concentrates on compulsory insurance and the government as provider as compared to private providers.
    Mr. Andrews also speaks on healthcare.
    Ludwig von Mises speaks about the political consequences of the welfare state. He begins by recounting the origin and semantics of the term "welfare state." He then concentrates on how the interests of individual members of a legislature is not the welfare of the nation, but the welfare of its constituents. He believes the system of interventionist government leads to inflation being the only way out.
    Jasper Crane compares the welfare state to cancer. Professor Hutt continues this analogy and also offers tactics on how to argue against the welfare state.
    1958 September 9, P.M. session. More discussions on the welfare state. The speakers are Felix Morley, including his analysis of James Madison; L. Baudin; Salvadori, who defines liberty as an economic system currently called capitalism and argues capitalism is a child of security; and Pfister.
    1958 September 10, A.M. session. Professor Milton Friedman, Mr. Sheffield, Professor F. A. Hayek, W. H. Hutt, and Henry Hazlitt.
    1958 September 10, noon session. Various speakers give their thoughts on inflation and monetary policy. The speakers are Eugenio Gudin (Brazil); Dr. Romulo Ferrero (Lima, Peru); Leonard E. Read (New York, U.S.A.); and Jacques Rueff (Paris-Luxembourg – English translation).
    1958 September 10, P.M. session. Volkmar Muthesius (Frankfurt, Germany – English translation), Milton Friedman (Chicago, Illinois, U.S.A.), C. Iversen (Copenhagen, Denmark), and Graham Hutton (London, England).
    1958 September 11, A.M. session. This session concerns labor unions, their influence on inflation, employee choice, labor history of the 20th century, and other related matters. The featured speakers are T. Wilson (Oxford, England), S. Petro (New York, U.S.A.), Goetz Brifs (Washington, D.C., U.S.A.), Jacques Rueff (Paris, France – English translation), S. W. Alexander (London, England), and Ludwig von Mises.
    Likely a continuation of the 1958 September 11, A.M. session. Speakers include Ludwig von Mises and Crawford H. Greenwalt, Pres of E. I. DuPont de Nemours Company.
    1958 September 11, P.M. session. This session focuses on agricultural economics. The speakers are W. H. Hutt (Capetown, South Africa), James C. Ingebretsen (California, U.S.A.), W. Hagenbuch (England), E. Bieri (Zurich, Switzerland), G. Briefs (U.S.A.), T. Wilson (England), S. Petro (U.S.A.), and L. Baudin (Paris, France – English translation).
    1958 September 12, A.M. session. W. M. Curtis (U.S.A.), Antony G. A. Fisher (England), H. Nichaus (Bonn, Germany), E. Gudin (Brazil), and Bruno Leoni (Italy).
    Part 11
    1958 September 12, P.M. session. This session focus on agricultural economics. The speakers are R. Ferrero (Peru), S. H. Frankel (Oxford, England), Jay Morrison (Seattle, Washington, U.S.A.), Felix Morley (Baltimore, Maryland, U.S.A.), L. Baudin (Paris, France – English translation), Harry D. Gideonese (Brooklyn, New York, U.S.A.) (on Russian visit), and Max Thurn (U.S.A.).
    Part 12
    1958 September 13, A.M. session. John Davenport (U.S.A.), D. McCord Wright (Montreal, Canada), Gustave Velasco (Mexico), and Nobutane Kinehi (Tokyo, Japan).
    Part 13
    1958 September 13, A.M. session. Frankel on escaping "the tyranny of the community," property rights, conditions that promote good government, and how to improve living conditions in Africa. Ludwig von Mises on positivity vs. negativity and central planning vs. individuals’ planning. Gudin on the roots of government intervention. Ferrero on the development of underdeveloped countries. John Davenport ponders defense issues. Hayek brings the conference to a close.
    Part 14
    A second copy of 1958 September 11, P.M. session, with possible additional content. Ludwig von Mises, cont’d. S. W. Alexander (London), W. H. Hutt (Capetown, South Africa), James C. Ingebretsen (California, U.S.A.), W. Hagenbuch (England), E. Bieri (Zurich, Switzlerland), G. Briefs (U.S.A.), T. Wilson (England), S. Petro (U.S.A.), and L. Baudin (Paris, France – English translation).
  - Mont Pèlerin Society meeting at Oxford, 1959 (Box 61)
    Use copy reference number: 81123_a_0005545
    Hayek (as Chairman) covers introductory and administrative issues. Briefs presents a paper entitled "Some Economic Aspects of the Pluralistic Society," which includes discussion of liberalism, freedom, and labor unions among other topics. Brozen and Frankel critique the paper with response by Briefs to Brozen.
    Frankel (continued), Hayek, Villey, Bauer, Briefs, Hayek (organizational remarks)
    Concerns monopolies. Professor Jewkes (Chairman), Professor Machlup, Professor Dennison
    Professor Dennison (continued), Professor Jewkes (time until coffee-break)
    Concerns monopolies. Professor Jewkes (Chairman), Professor Müller-Armack (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Professor Müller-Armack (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Professor Müller-Armack (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, George Schwartz, Henry Hazlitt, Griffin, Professor Dennison, Professor Machlup
    Professor Dennison (Chairman), Professor Leoni, Professor Shenfield, Mr. Kemp, Mr. Kelf-Cohen, Mr. Hazlitt, Professor Shenfiedl, McCord Right, Mr. Andrews, Professor Jewkes (remarks on the agenda)
    Concerns full employment policy. Hazlitt (Chairman), Pfister (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Pfister (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Pfister (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Pfister (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Hazlitt, Alchian, Hazlitt, Petro, Hahn
    Concerns full employment policy. Hahn (continued), Nyardi, Muthesius (Deutsch) viel zu leise, Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Muthesius (Deutsch) viel zu leise, Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Fertig – viel zu leise, Brozen, Harland Shaw, Alchian, Pfister, Frankel, Dr. Hunold (Angaben zur Tageseinteilung)
    Concerns imperfect freedom. Professor Frankel (Chairman), Henry Luce offers a critique of classical liberalism, Professor Hayek, Madariaga, Oliver Smedley, Professor Ropke
    Professor Ropke (continued), Jacques Rueff, Professor Frankel, MacCord Wright, Professor Frankel (Danksagung)
    Concerns agriculture. P. T. Bauer (chairman), Professor Brandt, Antony Fisher, Professor Nash, Professor Petersen, Professor Morrison, Professor Rostow, answer by Professor Brandt, P. T. Bauer
    Concerns Russia’s economic achievements. Professor Shenfield, Professor Nutter, W. Forster (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, Forster (Deutsch), Uebersetzung Grosse-Schware, American speaker (Hazlitt?), American speaker, Dr. Sennholz, Professor Allais
    Concerns Russia’s economic achievements (continued). Shenoy, P. T. Bauer, Karl Brandt, Goetz Briefs, Thurn, Dr. Petersen, MacCord Wright, Kelf-Cohen, Shenoy, A. Shenfield (Bemerkungen zum Tagesablauf)
    Concerns strategies and tactics. F.A. Hayek (introductory remarks), Harris, Seldon, Buchanan, Davenport, Velasco, Diana Spearman, Hayek (Zwischenbemerkung)
    Part 15
    L’Economie Francaise Apres L’Assainissement Financier. Speakers: Rueff (in French), Uebersetzung (English), Morley, Heilperin, Hornbostel, Hahn, Rueff, Morley
    Part 16
    L’Economie Francaise Apres L’Assainissement Financier (continued). Speakers: Professor Morley (Chairman), Jacques Rueff (majority of the tape), Professor Heilperin, Professor Hornbostel, Professor Hahn
    Part 17
    Concerns strategy and tactics. Professor Hayek (Chairman), Professor Van Sickle, P. T. Bauer, Dr. Hunold, Professor Brozen, Professor Kemp, O. Smedley, Professor Jewkes, Mr. Koether, Mr. Alexander, Professor Dietze, Davenport (Schlussworte), Professor Hayek (Bemerkungen zun Tagesablauf)
    Part 18
    Concerns education. Introductory remarks by John Davenport, Professor Morley*, Davenport, Professor Van Sickle, Professor Right (?), Professor Nutter, Davenport (Zwischenbemerkung), Professor Jewkes, Davenport (Zwischenbemerkung), Shaw, Dr. Hunold, Davenport (Zwischenbemerkung), Frankel, Davenport (Zwischenbemerkung)
    * bei 261 durch unsachgemass Behandlung des Bandes seitens Dr. V. Ilosvay nicht mehr abzuhoren. Herausnahme des Bandes soll in Gegenwart von Dr. Hunold erfolgt sein. Storung festgestellt: 4.1.60.
    Part 19
    Concerns insurance and health. Davenport, Dr. Campbell, Mrs. Campbell, geloscht durch falsche Behandlung seitens Dr. V. Ilosvay, festgestellt 4.1.1960, Davenport und Zwischenruf, nicht zu verstehen (Professor Jewkes, George Schwartz?), brit. Spreecher (Mr. Smedley), amerik. Spreecher (Professor Bunchanan?), Mrs. Widener, amerik. Spreecher, amerik. Spreecher (Mr. Hazlitt), amerik. Spreecher, Davenport, Schlusswort Professor Hayek
  - Mont Pèlerin Society meeting at Kassel, Germany, 1960 September 6-10 (Boxes 61-63)
    Use copy reference number: 81123_a_0005560
    6 September 1960 – 9:30-11:00. Chairman opens the conference. German economic minister Erhard on freedom and order, Rustow on freedom and communism.